Guide to the Henry Crosby Emery Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Henry Crosby Emery papers
1887-1912
MS 966
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(4 boxes)
The papers center on two aspects of Emery's activities: his teaching career at Yale and his service as chairman of the U.S. Tariff Board (1909-1913). Papers relating to the Board include correspondence, reports, statistics, and cloth samples collected in connection with the board's investigation of the carpet, wool, and cotton manufacturing industries, ca.1911-1912. Principal correspondents are members of the board, among them Alvin H. Sanders, James B. Reynolds, L. M. Spier, N. I. Stone, R. B. Horrow, and Charles A. Veditz.
Emery, Henry Crosby, 1872-1924
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. H. C. Emery, 1924.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Crosby Emery: economist; B.A., Bowdoin, 1892; M.A., Harvard, 1893; Ph.D., Columbia, 1896; professor at Bowdoin, 1896-1900; professor of political economy at Yale, 1900-1915; president of U.S. Tariff Board, 1909-1913; worked for Guaranty Trust Co., 1917-1924.
Scope and Contents
The papers center on two aspects of Emery's activities: his teaching career at Yale and his service as chairman of the U.S. Tariff Board (1909-1913). Papers relating to the Board include correspondence, reports, statistics, and cloth samples collected in connection with the board's investigation of the carpet, wool, and cotton manufacturing industries, ca.1911-1912. Principal correspondents are members of the board, among them Alvin H. Sanders, James B. Reynolds, L. M. Spier, N. I. Stone, R. B. Horrow, and Charles A. Veditz.
Arrangement
Arranged in two series: I. Correspondence. II. Topical Files.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Economics; Economists; Educators; Emery, Henry Crosby, 1872-1924; Horrow, R. B.; Reynolds, James Burton, 1870-; Sanders, Alvin Howard; Spier, Leslie, 1893-1961; Stone, N. I. (Nahum Isaac), 1873-1966; Verditz, Charles William Augustus, 1872-1926; United States International Trade Commission; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, Series I
  - 1909-1912 (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
- Topical Files, Series II
  - Board meetings, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
  - Cane sugar in Louisiana, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Carpets
    - General (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 655-XA - 655-XG (Box 2, Folder 15-21)
    - 655-XH - 655-XZ (Box 3, Folder 22-37)
    - 655-2Y (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Mills: Wage scales (Box 3, Folder 39-40)
  - Congressional bills, 1907-1912 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Cost data
    - England, 1909-1911 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Equipment (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Foreign (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - General expenses (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Ore prices, 1895-1910 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Samples (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Top making (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Woolen-yarn making (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Worsted yarn spinning (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Yarn (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 52-54)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 55-57)
  - Cotton
    - Industry (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Investments and earnings (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Textiles, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Economic Investigation, by H. C. Emery (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - "Economics", 1904 October - March 1906 (Box 6, Folder 62-73)
  - "Economics", 1906 April - May 1909 (Box 7, Folder 74-76)
  - Embroidery industry (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Employee list and wages (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Hearings
    - Boots and shoes, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - National Tanners Association, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 80)
    - Saddles and harness, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 80-A)
  - Interview of Mr. Stewart and Mr. Hinsberg, 1911 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Jackson documents, 1909 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Leathers, upper (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Paper (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Passport, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Priang (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Printed material (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Report to the Secretary of the Treasury (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Schedule "C" (Box 8, Folder 89-90)
  - Soap (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Statements
    - Bahnsen, C. and E. Meyer, 1911 (Box 8, Folder 92)
    - Ferguson, H., 1911 (Box 8, Folder 93)
    - MacLea, R., 1911 (Box 8, Folder 94)
    - Power, T., 1911 (Box 8, Folder 95)
    - Sears, E., 1911 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Statements and bills, 1912 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Tariff Board reports (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - U.S.- Denmark trade, 1887-1911 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Wool (Box 8, Folder 100-103)